<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  

  <title>tortoise & badger</title>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    <icon>http://candychang.github.io/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
  <subtitle>Candy Chang's personal website and portfolio</subtitle>
  <link href="http://candychang.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://candychang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  <updated>2016-06-30T00:00:04+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://candychang.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Candy Chang</name>
    <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
    <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Bernal Heights App</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/bernal-heights/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/bernal-heights</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/bhnc_room.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn&quot; href=&quot;http://bernal-heights.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Check out the project&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/candychang/bernal-heights&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pivotaltracker.com/n/projects/1543993&quot;&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;bhnc app homepage&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on a team of five computer science/EECS students during the Spring 2016
semester to create a web application promoting community engagement and safety 
in Bernal Heights, San Francisco. Our client was the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://donatenow.networkforgood.org/BHNC?code=Website+button&quot; title=&quot;BHNC Link&quot;&gt;Bernal Heights Neighborhood Center&lt;/a&gt; (BHNC),
a small non-profit that provides social programs for seniors and youth, 
and fosters neighborhood activism to solve local problems. We made this as part
of CS169, Software Engineering as a Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;involvement&quot;&gt;Involvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone on the team contributed to both design and implementation, which was 
a really great experience after group projects with mostly distributed roles. As
one of the two team members with some prior Rails experience, I was heavily involved
in implementation and learning how to manage testing and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-stack, agile, TDD and BDD development on Ruby on Rails, following MVC and RESTful practices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and implementation of the admin-side workflow for  staff accounts, hotspots and events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managed Git repo, continuous integration and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low-fi mockups, including the hotspot form experience on mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-person interviews and persona generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design&lt;/em&gt;: Pencil and paper, whiteboard, POP, Adobe Illustrator, browser prototyping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Development&lt;/em&gt;: Ruby on Rails, Haml, Sass, Javascript, Pivotal Tracker, Travis CI, 
CodeClimate, Cucumber, Rspec, Heroku&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-workflow&quot;&gt;Team Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was very much about learning by doing — not only Rails and its
various gems, but also the agile workflow. We had daily standups in Slack,
wrote, pointed and assigned user stories and features in Pivotal Tracker,
and practiced test-driven development with continuous integration and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Week one: Client meeting, create user stories/mockups for the features this 
          iteration, write Cucumber/Rspec tests, meet with instructors for mini-review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Week two: Work on our stories until all tests pass green, deploy for user testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of managing our repo, as well as continuous integration and deployment. 
We also had a PM who looked after Pivotal Tracker and made sure our standups got done,
and a point person for contacting our client and submitting progress reports to our 
instructors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customer-needs&quot;&gt;Customer Needs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with Ailed and Esme, BHNC chairs of community engagement and public
safety, for the majority of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most successful programs Ailed and Esme manage at BHNC is the hotspot 
walk. Residents submit hotspot forms about problems in the neighborhood that 
affect public safety, and BHNC staff aggregate the information. Then, they
invite the police and relevant city departments to walk with BHNC staff and neighbors 
around the neighborhood to see the problems in person. This is often a more effective
way of getting problems fixed than relying on individual requests from residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/sample_hotspot_redacted.png&quot; alt=&quot;sample hotspot form&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Example of submitted hotspot form, contact information redacted&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, staff had to process over 200 of these forms per walk. One dedicated neighbor 
was inputting all the information by hand into Google Maps in order to get a 
visualization of problem spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ailed also wanted to get residents more involved in resolving their own problems.
Besides hotspot walks, there are also community meetings, park cleanups, and other
events that Ailed wanted to easily share with residents. She had tried using Nextdoor
but found it too time-consuming to manage and too cluttered with other topics
to get her information across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on these conversations with Ailed and Esme, we established three
main functionalities of the requested web app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gather, manage and share hotspot form information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a centralized calendar for BHNC and resident-created events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share useful resources with residents in one accessible location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-process&quot;&gt;Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/bh_flow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;admin flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out with a broad brainstorming session for how the app
would be put together. Each iteration, if needed, we would sketch out how the
new features would fit into the current plan and run those by Ailed and Esme.
Within our team, we often tried to do group design on the whiteboard,
and shared our sketches over Slack when meeting up wasn’t possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of our big questions, we made low-fi prototypes in POP and travelled in person 
to SF to have Ailed, Esme and Bernal residents do some user testing. I was in charge of 
making a wizard version of the hotspot form to compare against the single-page version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://popapp.in/w/projects/56eb0d6243b167426a24622f/embedded&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-decisions&quot;&gt;Design Decisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a few significant changes to our designs based on the feedback we got
from user testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testers assumed that the first step to submitting a hotspot form was specifying a location. 
Many attempted to “drop a pin” on to the map. We initially had location come after specifying 
the type of issue being reported. Seeing testers’ reactions, however, we went back to the 
drawing board. Although dropping a pin was a natural reaction for users, we felt that in 
reality being able to do that accurately, especially if on a mobile browser, would be difficult. 
Instead, we added a search bar to the map; searching for a location would drop a pin and pop 
up a link to fill out the rest of the hotspot form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/hotspot_location.png&quot; alt=&quot;hotspot location&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Hotspot with location search&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign-in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we planned to use sign-in and 3rd party authentication to eliminate the need for filling
in name and contact information on every submitted form. This seemed like a time-saving feature
that would encourage more people to submit. After user testing, however, we eliminated sign-in
for residents. Testers said requiring a user name and password made the application feel unwelcoming; 
the sign-in page was more of a barrier to them than filling out their information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hotspot Form Wizard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up implementing a wizard to walk through the required information for hotspot
forms, since most testers reported feeling more overwhelmed by the single-page prototype,
and visibily enjoyed using the wizard version more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;admin-workflow&quot;&gt;Admin Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/admin_homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;admin homepage&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Final admin homepage&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I ended up taking on many of the admin-side user stories, I thought a lot about
Ailed’s personality and the contexts in which she’d be using this app. Working
in a small non-profit already meant being strapped for time and resources; in addition,
Ailed was a new mother. I decided to create a homepage that would prompt Ailed if anything needed her 
attention — for example, if any new events had been submitted and needed approval —
and would provide immediate access to her most common tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other small details worked in by the last iteration: if signed in, the admin doesn’t 
need to fill out name, contact info or organization name on any of the forms. The events 
calendar has a reminder about the number of unapproved events. Clicking on a pin in the 
admin hotspot map will show a link to the entire form submission; earlier iterations,
the only way to view that information was going through the list of hotspots below the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/hotspot_admin_1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;bhnc calendar&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Admin hotspots page&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/bh_visit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;me at bhnc&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;At in-person meeting with Ailed and Esme&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was extremely rewarding working with a non-profit for the semester,
especially because I know firsthand how difficult it is to get projects like
these off the ground without outside help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of software development, we learned a lot about how to communicate 
effectively. While Ailed had a general idea of what she wanted, she didn’t have 
a clear picture of the possibilities or limitations of a web application. 
We found that having visual representations ready while discussing features
was the best way to elicit useful feedback, absent opportunities to speak face to face. 
We did manage to make two trips to BHNC in person, and those meetings were the most
fruitful. Not only did we clarify many questions, but we also got a feel for the
characteristics of Bernal Heights, BHNC, and some of its residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile development was a first for most of us, and the test-driven process
was especially taxing at first. In addition, we had to keep on revising our back-end
relationship models as user stories and features were added or discarded.
At the same time, our workflow had everyone involved in discussing both UX
and implementation, and I enjoyed that immensely. I also liked learning how to
test with Cucumber, which made it easier to focus discussion about app
features on user needs instead of specific technologies or implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we won’t all be continuing to work on this app, I couldn’t have asked 
for a better group of people to work with during the semester.
I’ll miss getting their Slack notifications :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/bh_group_pic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team picture&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, one of my teammates and I have committed 
to staying in touch with Ailed and maintaining the app post-graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make UX better for certain groups of neighbors - those who would like to print
records out or want confirmation of their submissions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the attach photo functionality to hotspot forms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cluster hotspots that are about the same location&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unify visual design, and also match look and feel of app better to the characteristics of BHNC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Zest</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/zest/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/zest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/j18eTHD7LU4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An IoT cooking experience integrating sensors and existing devices. 
Worked with a team of five mechanical engineers. Class project for ME110, 
New Product Development. Prompt from our sponsors, Samsung: 
“Leisure and Entertainment,” ideally something using speakers and sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;involvement&quot;&gt;Involvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participated in all aspects of product development process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created interactive prototypes in Marvel and Invision&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepared decks and led presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pencil and paper, whiteboard, post-its, Marvel, Invision, Adobe Illustrator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;concept-generation&quot;&gt;Concept Generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given a broad prompt “make an IoT product within the theme of Leisure
and Entertainment” and told we could do pretty much what we wanted. As a
result, we revisited the brainstorm stage many times and conducted several rounds of 
interviews as we slowly narrowed our focus to enhancing the cooking experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;slick-carousel&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_brainstorm_a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorm ideas&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_brainstorm_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorm ideas&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_brainstorm_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorm ideas&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_brainstorm_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorm ideas&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_brainstorm_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;brainstorm ideas&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Some of the ideas I contributed to the brainstorming sessions&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot by visiting people in person and asking 
them to show me how they did things. For example, one of my interviewees 
said he enjoyed listening to music and talkshows while cooking, but didn’t bring
up anything inconvenient about the process. When I asked 
to see how he set up his cooking space, however, he grabbed his laptop and 
placed it on top of the trashcan! It had become such a regular thing for him 
that he didn’t think to bring it up when I asked at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/trashcan_music.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;laptop on trashcan&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user needs we concluded from our interviews:
- control devices without getting them dirty or breaking workflow
- adapt to changing environment with little user involvement (sounds, placement in the kitchen)
- improve cooking skills
- share accomplishments with friends family
- figure out what to cook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototypes&quot;&gt;Prototypes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_midterm_prototypes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;three prototypes&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We created three different prototypes for our midterm tradeshow. They each tested a 
different aspect of our cooking ideas. Mr. Pan was the interactive cooking teacher,
the Smart Cutting Board could display videos and recipes, and Basket was a cooking
challenge app where friends could challenge each other to cook with random ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototypes were at different levels of fidelity and functionality to test different
things. Mr. Pan was hooked up to an Arduino and would react to someone “cooking” inside
of it. The Smart Cutting Board was literally an iPad displaying a few screen mockups. 
Basket was a low-fi interactive prototype made in Marvel, to see if people understood
the concept and found it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of creating the Basket prototype. I chose to use Marvel as my prototyping
tool because I could take pictures of my sketched mockups and turn those directly into
my prototype. I didn’t want to create something in Illustrator or Photoshop so early on,
because that would keep people from giving feedback on the concept itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;centered&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://marvelapp.com/d95b0j?emb=1&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We distributed surveys to everyone who tried our products, asking when and how often they
would think about using the product, as well as what their experience with the prototype was
like. We also asked which of the products they enjoyed the most out of the three. We collected
approximately 30 surveys total. The responses confirmed most of the conclusions from our user interviews,
and brought a few new insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users wanted notifications and alerts during the cooking process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They didn’t want to buy an entirely new device or kitchen appliance - they would prefer if the product
were sold separately and could integrate with their existing products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They liked having recipe suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They wanted to be able to control their music while cooking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;concept-selection&quot;&gt;Concept Selection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_concept_selection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;concept matrix&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post-tradeshow, we evaluated the three prototypes against what we learned from 
the survey feedback. Mr. Pan and the Smart Cutting Board both were well-received
at the tradeshow. People liked the learning aspect, as well as the integrated
nature of the controls. One problem they had with both devices, however, was
that they would have to buy a completely new appliance in order to get these
features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we conducted competitive analysis, we also found a Mr. Pan-like product on 
Kickstartr already — an intelligent pan that used temperature information
to help users cook more accurately. There were also a variety of recipe and
cooking apps for smartphones and tablets out in the market already.
To figure out how to find a competitive advantage in this market, we made
a concept matrix and decided to create a completely new product, taking
relevant ideas from each prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key change from our previous prototypes was a shift from an intelligent
cooking device, to sensors that could be attached to existing appliances.
To lock down finer details of our new prototype, we conducted
about 30 more short interviews to find the most needed features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-prototype&quot;&gt;Final Prototype&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;zest demo&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sensor set-up demo. The prototypes were 3-D printed by one of my teammates.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zest is a collection of sensors that can be attached to various cooking implements
and cookware. When they sync with the mobile application, they can provide
contextual cooking instructions and notifications. The sensors also act as
volume control, so no matter where you are in your kitchen you can adjust your
entertainment as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_roadmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;recipe flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Stages of an amateur cook&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed Zest with the above roadmap in mind. I spoke with many people who
didn’t cook regularly, or wanted to but weren’t able to for one reason or another.
For some people, it was really about avoiding doing dishes; for others, the 
“ominvore’s dilemma” struck them every time they opened the fridge to try and
figure out what to cook. Some people simply didn’t want to touch raw food
or go through the effort of preparing it when take-out was readily available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make a product that could support people at every stage of the
cooking process, transitioning them from finding it a chore, to becoming eager
to learn more, to getting creative and sharing their success. We even thought
about adding an “orchestra mode,” where music would change according to
a user’s actions in the kitchen — a throwback to Mr. Pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of creating the mobile app portion of the prototype. It was
challenging to work out the recipe screens, and they could have done with
more user testing if we had the time. Zest provided not only cooking instructions,
but music control as well — this meant parceling out screen estate accordingly
and deciding what to show and what to hide away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_prototype_stitched.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rough UI sketches&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Rough sketches for UI design&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I used Invision to string together the views, since we
wanted something more polished to test out at the final showcase. Invision can
only handle one orientation at a time, though, so the prototype is split into
two parts for easier desktop viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://invis.io/F97N9TBHS&quot;&gt;Onboarding&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://invis.io/9U2X87YK4&quot;&gt;Cooking Instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;slick-carousel&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/invision_screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;invision screenshot&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_onboarding_flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;onboarding flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_choose_recipe.png&quot; alt=&quot;choose recipe flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_recipe_screens_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;recipe flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_recipe_screens_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;recipe flow&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we changed product ideas near the end of the semester, we didn’t get
to test Zest out with that many users. If we had more time, I would have wanted to
do some actual kitchen testing with this prototype. Would they be comfortable with 
these sensors stuck all over their appliances? Do the steps and the cooking timers 
make sense? An important consideration our mentors told us to think about was 
repeatability. Would sensor set-up be troublesome enough that users would decide
not to integrate it into their usual workflow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important lesson learned from this project was how to factor in design 
within a business context. How can you design something that can win market 
share from other products, or generate a primary market, like Apple once did 
with the iPhone? Coming up with something that meets user needs is a first step, 
but other considerations come into play — available technology, profitability, 
manufacturability, sustainability and so on. A product can only survive if it 
manages to balance everything; no wonder iteration is so often a fitting 
development method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big part of this experience was working within a multi-disciplinary team.
It was great to see different perspectives from my teammates, who 
were mechanical engineers, with one also pursuing architecture and one
doubling with EECS. If I had been on a team of only CS students, I think we 
would have mostly explored software-only solutions. With more variety in thinkers at 
the table, we managed to explore many more possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/zest_members.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Samsung IoTeam members!&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>PiE Annual Report</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/annual-report/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/annual-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/annual_report_map_pages.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/assets/annual_report.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot;&gt;Download Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PiE’s annual reports have historically been 15+ page word documents sent out to
sponsors at the end of every fiscal year. I redesigned and wrote most of the
copy for the 2014-2015 report, which covers PiE during my year as director. 
I incorporated plenty of images and statistics to make our impact clearer to 
sponsors, alumni, the general public, and potential donors. As of spring 2016, 
sending out this report has helped raise over $10,000 in funding from sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Opportune</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/opportune/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/opportune</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_feature.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hackster.io/mango-innovations/opportune-9cf9a9&quot;&gt;Hackster.io Project Report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn-secondary&quot; href=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/assets/PalantirRecruiterContextualInquiry.pdf&quot;&gt;Full Contextual Inquiry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/114516289&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A proof-of-concept for a Qualcomm Toq smartwatch app for recruiters. 
Class project for CS160, User Interface Design. Worked on a team of five
computer science majors; we split the roles into two designers, three
developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;involvement&quot;&gt;Involvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project I was most involved in user research and visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participated in brainstorming and illustrated initial selected concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performed contextual inquiry with Palantir recruiters, then crafted our 
personas using the information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made hi-fi mockups for Toq watch and Android views&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created presentation decks and led pitches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pencil and paper, Photoshop, Illustrator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brainstorm&quot;&gt;Brainstorm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed possible smartwatch applications as a group, clustering similar
ideas together and building off of other people’s ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/mangoinnovations_brainstorm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;post-it brainstorming&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/mango_innovations_firstideas-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;news app&quot; width=&quot;220px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/mango_innovations_firstideas-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;food app&quot; width=&quot;220px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/mango_innovations_firstideas-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;carpool app&quot; width=&quot;220px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I illustrated our top three concepts to present at our initial design review.
In the end, however, we chose a fourth idea that we bounced around during the 
review session: an app that would enable users to exchange contact information 
using common hand gestures. We further narrowed down our focus user group to 
recruiters and job seekers at career fairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-studies&quot;&gt;User Studies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/career_fair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;career fair sketches&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited career fairs to make observations and find interview subjects. Happily, 
at one engineering career fair, I even got permission to perform contextual inquiry 
with a group of Palantir recruiters. Here are some of the observations and takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/270261772%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-SYHe8&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=false&amp;amp;show_user=false&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career fairs are really crowded, busy and loud. If you put something down or give 
something away it’s hard to keep track of it. Reaching over tables to put away 
stacks of collected resumes, or to just get a water bottle, is physically inconvenient.
Having someone at the table coordinating is extremely useful, especially when trying
to grab things or put things away is difficult due to lack of space. Getting people’s
attention is difficult due to the noise. In addition, the layout and space constraints 
mean that even tapping someone on the shoulder isn’t an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handshake and greeting come before looking at resume. The goal is to get personal 
face time with candidates and carry on a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note-taking: The engineers and recruiters take short notes, usually only three or 
four lines. They never write on the front of resumes to avoid bias, only the back. 
Palantir uses post-its, in addition to having a pen and clipboard for the resume. 
Post-its go on the back of the clipboard; they’re there in case there are doublesided
resumes, or there are people who didn’t bring resumes and they need to write down 
contact info. Things to write down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The initials of whoever talked to the student, for later reference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The student’s interest/possible team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internship/full time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there was a technical question, the problem and the rating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post-fair, recruiters will have to manually scan the resumes into whatever CMS
they use to track applicants. This is the part of the process that has some
companies turning to using tablets at career fairs. Palantir doesn’t use them,
however, because they’ve found it stalls conversations and causes backlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantitative Observations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are rough counts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average number of students at the booth was 8.4. This was a pretty high number
in comparison to many other booths, given Palantir’s popularity. Keeping wait
times down is important because some students will just leave if they have
to stand in line for too long. Palantir’s recruiters aim for five minutes per
person, but it’s really hard to keep to that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/palantir_student_graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;students at booth over time&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things they carried: the top five ways students held their resumes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plastic or other cheap folder (26)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just papers (18)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File folder (16)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notebook (7)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manila envelope (4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the findings from this contextual inquiry, as well as other user interviews
conducted by teammates, we came up with a few important user needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facilitate face-to-face conversations with candidates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note down necessary information about candidate during conversation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect all information in a way that eliminates the need for manual entry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manageable with only one free hand, limited movements and loud surrounding environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototype-design&quot;&gt;Prototype Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/toq_tagging.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tagging candidate info&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed our prototype to fulfill features based on the key user needs
we highlighted from our studies: contact exchange, tagging, and third-party 
integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initially hoped to implement note-taking, but given the Toq watch’s limited
capabilities, as well as the small screen estate, we turned
to tagging instead. This was a viable alternative, since our user studies 
showed that recruiters take very little notes, and they usually have predictable
inputs that can be set beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make digital submission of information as painless as possible,
we felt the best way was to integrate with platforms like LinkedIn, GitHub
and Behance to help candidates showcase their experience and make it simple
to port all the information into a company’s CMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ui-design&quot;&gt;UI Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of the visual/UI design for the prototype’s watch and mobile views.
This included designing the logo: a stylized representation of a handshake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;opportune logo&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing for the Toq watch was mostly about figuring out what was
supported by the SDK, and what things to give up on at the design stage
because of hardware and software limitations. Possible interactions like
bumping watches or sliding cards across to each other were ruled out at
the sketching stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_sketches_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;toq sketches&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Smartwatch sketches&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge for the mobile views was working out how to fit
so much information within a small screen. I ended up going with an
accordion pattern, with the main job title and company visible and
details hidden by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_sketches_a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rough UI sketches&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sketching possible layouts&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;slick-carousel&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_initial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;initial login&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_login.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;logging in&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_schools.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;school view&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_candidates.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;school view&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/opportune_profile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;school view&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;Mockups for Framer.js&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot about designing around limitations during this
project. The watch form factor influenced all our technical and product decisions;
we had to set aside several of our ideas because they didn’t work with the small
screen estate or the possible modes of interaction. We also had to consider
likely user bases — smartwatches are not ubiquitous, and certain user groups,
like high-salaried tech workers, are more likely to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked on this project around the time when the Apple Watch was first being
promoted. Smartwatch technology and design has advanced since then, and it’s
exciting to think that some of our early ideas might be possible to achieve now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/mango_final_group_pic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;opportune group picture&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CaptureProof</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/captureproof/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/captureproof</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/captureproof_postits.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I was a Design and UI/UX intern at &lt;a href=&quot;http://captureproof.com/ CaptureProof link&quot;&gt;CaptureProof&lt;/a&gt;, 
a medical media startup that provides a HIPAA-compliant platform for sharing photos and video
between doctors and patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iphone-mockups&quot;&gt;iPhone Mockups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of the mockups I made for the iPhone app. For all my work, I first
sketched out ideas and ran them by the CEO. Once she was satisfied, I made
higher fidelity mockups in Photoshop. By the end of my internship I had produced 
mockups for all the main functionalities available in the mobile app at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/captureproof_sketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;UI sketches&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sketches&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/captureproof_process.png&quot; alt=&quot;initial screen to final&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;From initial view to re-design&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wireframes&quot;&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn&quot; href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B0ssrMcyToYUQUJnOG5WaDhiTDA&quot;&gt;See all wireframes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/captureproof_balsamiq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Balsamiq mockup of sign-up page&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The sign-up process&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEO wanted a re-design of the onboarding process, to make the mobile
and web applications feel consistent. I was tasked with creating Balsamiq
wireframes for inviting patients and onboarding doctors through the web
app, then re-creating a similar flow with the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dérive</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/derive/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/derive</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_feature.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/viN2o8-oxXo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UI design for a hypothetical navigation application based on the Situationist’s 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cddc.vt.edu/sionline/si/theory.html Theory of the Dérive&quot;&gt;dérive&lt;/a&gt; , 
where one “drifts” in an unplanned way through a city, subconsciously guided
by the architecture and geography of the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users of this application can choose a location, invite friends to
dérive to the destination as well, and then select the kind of wandering 
experience they would like to have before arriving at their destination.
In contrast to most navigation applications, which give you the fasted route
to your destination, Dérive’s focus is on crafting a unique journey to that
destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illustrator, Photoshop, Framer.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;details&quot;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the idea of wandering through a city, taking the time to really
look at the surroundings instead of worrying about the final destination.
I wanted the app to feel whimsical to users, with copy, visuals and interactions
encouraging them to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_colors.png&quot; alt=&quot;derive color palette&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually start off with rough sketches of screens and how they flow together, 
but for this project, I started with the colors and patterns above. There
are far more colors than I usually work with, because I wanted to represent
the possibilities of adventure, and the many facets of a place waiting
to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_island_plane.png&quot; alt=&quot;island and plane graphics&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plane and the island were offhand explorations I made while working on the
background patterns. They fit the spirit of the app, so I ended up integrating
them into the visual design. The plane helped express movement from screen
to screen, and the island became the symbol for the final location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interactions&quot;&gt;Interactions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derive is supposed to inspire exploration, so I felt a typical form with
radio buttons or dropdowns would be too boring when it came to expressing
route preferences. Since the prompt required that users be able to 
customize several different elements of the trip, a more interesting
presentation would also keep users from feeling like stopping halfway through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;slick-carousel&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_activity_drawn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;activity level&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_safety.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;safety level&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_environ_vars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;environment preferences&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;centered-img&quot; src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/derive_randomizer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;randomizer&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the typical question for activity level is something along the lines of 
“light, average, or heavy workout?” When you think about energy level and
typical workouts though, the intensity is rarely a constant amount. 
There are also physical limitations to consider; some people need to avoid 
stairs or hilly regions as much as possible. Being able to draw out how you’d 
like your journey to feel, instead of specifying these factors in words or
dropdown selections would be pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first time using Framer.js as a prototyping tool. It was a great
experience being able to code interactions for individual elements instead
of relying on the per-screen animations of tools like Marvel or Invision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on this project, I just wanted to have more interesting 
interactions. Interesting, however, can’t really trump usability. If
I had a second iteration of this prototype, these would be just a few
of the questions I’d work on: Is there some kind of confirmation that the app 
has interpreted your drawing correctly, and a way to adjust the result? How 
can a user tell right now what exactly a “safe” or a “risky” trip would
entail? Would a user have to repeat these settings each time they wanted
to go on a derive, or is there a way to save these customizations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now, I’m still in love with the concept of the dérive, probably
because I find cultural landscape studies and thinking about how infrastructure 
and buildings impact how we act and feel to be really fascinating. It’s similar 
to thinking about how physical and digital interfaces influence people’s actions
and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, in this age of Google Maps and door to door delivery for almost anything,
dérives would be a good reminder to savor the journey — and make the effort
to have one in the first place! — instead of skipping directly to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Watch in the Wild</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/watch-in-the-wild/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/portfolio/watch-in-the-wild</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/watch_materials.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A low-fi prototype for a team roster/attendance watch application. 
Demonstrates once cycle of iterative process, from 
interviewing to brainstorming to prototyping to testing.
It’s very near and dear to me, because any chance to do some crafting
instead of just making digital mockups is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackster.io/candychang/design-01-watches-in-the-wild-ca1f16 Hackster.io post&quot;&gt;Hackster.io post&lt;/a&gt; for the full design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;328&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hackster.io/candychang/design-01-watches-in-the-wild-ca1f16/embed?use_route=project&quot; width=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://candychang.github.io/sketchbook/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://candychang.github.io/sketchbook/hello-world</id>
    <author>
      <name>Candy Chang</name>
      <uri>http://candychang.github.io/</uri>
      <email>candyichang@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://candychang.github.io/images/notebook_a_1024x256.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m planning to use this as a digital sketchbook.
It’s an experiment, half to get me to create more content on a regular basis, and half to log the random stuff I do have in my notebooks etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’ll be writing, sometimes it’ll be random crafts I’ve made for someone, sometimes it’ll actually be sketches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
</feed>